<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Nevin Kollanoor</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Nevin Kollanoor</description>
    <image>
      <title>Nevin Kollanoor</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Predictably Irrational- Dan Ariely</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/books/predictably_irrational/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/books/predictably_irrational/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-decoy-effect&#34;&gt;1. Decoy Effect:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often people don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want until these see things in context. Everything is relevant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we are always looking at things in relation to others. A perceived size of circle changes based on whether it&amp;rsquo;s placed among other smaller circles or bigger circles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the reason why a print+online subscription is the best seller when you have a decoy option like print only for almost the same price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We take the decision based on what we do know - print +online for 150$ is better than print only for 125$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing a new most expensive entree in a restaurant menu improves the sale of next most expensive entree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A man&amp;rsquo;s satisfaction with his salary depends on whether he makes more than his wife&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s husband&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-arbitrary-coherence&#34;&gt;2. Arbitrary Coherence:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second price auction?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first seen price in a new product category serves as an anchor - as long as you seriously contemplate to buy it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is same reason why people are initially not willing to pay higher rents when they move to expensive cities even when their wages are calibrated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These anchors have an enduring affect and we see ourselves coming back to this anchor diet comparison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of zero cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zero is the source of emotional excitement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every transaction has an upside and a downside. Free transactions gives the illusion that there’s bio downside. Our high inclination to loss aversion makes it far more attractive than it actually is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon saw an increase in AOV when it introduced free shipping above 20$. They saw this increase everywhere except in France where they charged a reduced fee of 20 cents for these high value orders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zero is not another discount, it’s a place. Difference between 2 and 1 is small. But the difference between 1 and zero is huge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-social-and-market-norms&#34;&gt;4. Social and Market norms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People might work more for a cause than cash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 2 different worlds we live in. One where market norms apply and one where social norms apply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once social norm meets the market norm, social norm goes away for a long long time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-influence-of-arousal&#34;&gt;5. Influence of arousal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our inability to understand ourselves doesn’t improve with experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-problem-of-procrastination-and-self-control&#34;&gt;6. Problem of procrastination and self control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resisting temptation and instilling self control are general human goals, and repeatedly failing to achieve them is the source of much of our misery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road to hell is paved with good intentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre commitment (self imposed challenge) is one tool that solves this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-the-high-price-of-ownership&#34;&gt;7. The high price of ownership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we own something, we start to value it more than others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students who won a lottery to a basketball game were willing to sell it at 2400$ while while students who didn’t make the lottery were willing to buy at only 170$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We fall in love for what we already have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case of large transactions, approach it as if you are a non-owner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-why-options-distract-us-from-iit-main-objective&#34;&gt;8. Why options distract us from iit main objective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Studies have shown that When given options, even if we know the expected value of each of these options, we still choose to explore 🤷🏻‍♂️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-the-effect-of-expectations&#34;&gt;9. The effect of expectations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previously held impressions affect the interpretation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you tell people in advance that something might be distasteful, odds are good that they will agree with you - because of their expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-the-power-of-price&#34;&gt;10. The power of price&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price/cost can act as placebo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-why-dealing-with-cash-makes-us-more-honest&#34;&gt;12. Why dealing with cash makes us more honest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the opportunity to cheat is in context of something that’s a few steps removed, or even one step removed from actual cash, we all cheat, to a greater extent at that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the reason why you see flagrant cheating in insurance claims, backdating stock options, audit books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In these scenarios, we tend to rationalize and be dishonest by telling ourselves that e we are not being dishonest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;13-beer-and-free-lunches&#34;&gt;13. Beer and Free lunches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we order out loud in sequence, we tend to order a drink different to what others ordered on table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things you can see when you slow down - Haemin Sunim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/books/things_you_see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/books/things_you_see/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;rest&#34;&gt;REST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that the world is objectively joyful or sad and produces the corresponding feeling in us. Feelings originate with the mind projecting it&amp;rsquo;s subjective experience on to the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our reality is not the infinitely expanding cosmos. But the small part we choose to focus on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not the situations that are troubling us, but our perspective on it. Tsunamies are terrifying not just because of the water, but because of the objects that are hurled at us. We feel unhappy not just because of what happened, but because of the swirling thoughts of what happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t struggle to heal your wounds. Just pour time into your heart and wait. When the wounds are ready, they will heal on their own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself how your work helps others regardless of how insignificantly or indirectly. As you focus more on others, you can reconnect with the meaning and purpose for your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With love in our hearts, you will find the most mundane things beautiful. Without love in our hearts, we find the world meaningless, and random. Without love in our hearts, we will become strangers even to our family and friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t give up upon receiving criticism. Brush aside what people who don&amp;rsquo;t know you have to say.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life teaches us through our mistakes. When you make a mistake, simply ask yourself what you are meant to learn from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mindfulness&#34;&gt;MINDFULNESS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When people who don&amp;rsquo;t know you well admire you, they are seeing their projected illusion not your real self. In contrast when people who know you well respect you, it&amp;rsquo;s probably because you deserve it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you push back against an unchangeable no, you will suffer in the process and miss other opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entirety of an enlightened person can be summarized into &amp;lsquo;complete acceptance to what is&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating the present through the memories of the past can cause sadness. Change is inevitable, embrace it and welcome it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our consciousness may desire money, power and prestige. But the subconscious desires selfless love, harmony, humour, beauty, sacredness, peace and acceptance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;passion&#34;&gt;PASSION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a mistake to equate our own eagerness with effectiveness. Getting the job done well is more important than one&amp;rsquo;s feeling a of doing a good job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One&amp;rsquo;s own zealous efforts can sometimes get in the way of achieving the desired outcome especially if one is not able to see the needs of others working together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s dangerous to have passion without wisdom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A vow to help others can immense energy from inside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many conflicts can be resolved if we try to look at things from the other&amp;rsquo;s pov.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you get angry while debating right and wrong, your enraged voice just conceded defeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;relationships&#34;&gt;RELATIONSHIPS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversations tend to become boring when we are in the clutches of politeness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;love&#34;&gt;LOVE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be as gentle in ending a relationship, as you were starting it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anger without reason, could be an indication of crush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;life&#34;&gt;LIFE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down the things that you want to do for yourself before you die and do it one by one. No one needs to know about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dream big, start small&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your thoughts become your words, words become your behavior, behaviors become your habits, your habits become your values and your values become your destiny. So keep them positive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When our greed is awakened, we are cheated. Swindlers use this often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reward for someone who works hard is more work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we are quick to grant a favor, people quickly forget their gratitude. If we grant a favor with several conditions, then people express immense gratitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-future&#34;&gt;THE FUTURE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live your life not to satisfy others, but to fulfill your own desires&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life isn&amp;rsquo;t a 100 meter race against your friends, but a life long marathon against yourself. Don&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed that you are slightly behind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you wake up in the morning, tell yourself &amp;ldquo;I will not spend today passively, doing what others ask me to do. I will take the lead and forge my own destiny&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a goal for the week. A significant accomplishment can be traced back to a single thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About career choices - The truth is that other people do not really think about you that much. If you think you will enjoy something, don&amp;rsquo;t overthink it. Just do it. Even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t turn out to be what you thought it would be, you will appreciate what it taught you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
